<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><cmd:CMD xmlns:cmd="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/ http://catalog.clarin.eu/ds/ComponentRegistry/rest/registry/1.1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934/xsd" CMDVersion="1.1"><cmd:Header><cmd:MdCreator>test</cmd:MdCreator><cmd:MdCreationDate xmlns:clariah="http://www.clariah.eu/" clariah:epoch="1737973642">2025-01-27</cmd:MdCreationDate><cmd:MdSelfLink>unl://3</cmd:MdSelfLink><cmd:MdProfile>clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934</cmd:MdProfile><cmd:MdCollectionDisplayName/></cmd:Header><cmd:Resources><cmd:ResourceProxyList/><cmd:JournalFileProxyList/><cmd:ResourceRelationList/><cmd:IsPartOfList/></cmd:Resources><cmd:Components><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions><cmd:status>under construction</cmd:status><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea><cmd:DREidentifier>DRE_CHI_003</cmd:DREidentifier><cmd:typeOfInstitution>international organisation</cmd:typeOfInstitution><cmd:Names><cmd:authorisedForm>Documenta – Centar za suočavanje s prošlošću</cmd:authorisedForm><cmd:parallelForm>Documenta – Centre for Dealing with the Past</cmd:parallelForm><cmd:otherForm>Documenta</cmd:otherForm></cmd:Names></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea><cmd:city xml:lang="en">Zagreb</cmd:city><cmd:country xml:lang="en">Croatia</cmd:country><cmd:telephoneNumber>'+385 1 457 2398 </cmd:telephoneNumber><cmd:faxNumber>'+385 1 457 2399</cmd:faxNumber><cmd:email>kontakt@documenta.hr</cmd:email><cmd:website>https://documenta.hr/en/</cmd:website><cmd:locationsAndAdresses><cmd:Adress>Selska cesta 112c</cmd:Adress></cmd:locationsAndAdresses></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea><cmd:history xml:lang="en">Centre for Peace, Non-Violence and Human Rights Osijek, Centre for Peace Studies, Civic Committee for Human Rights and Croatian Helsinki Committee decided to found Documenta – Centre for Dealing with the Past in an attempt to encourage the process of dealing with the past and establishing factual truth about the war and to contribute to shifting of the discussion from the level of dispute over facts (the number of killed people, etc.) towards a dialogue on interpretations.  The key reason for making this attempt was the silence about and falsification of war crimes and other war-related events in the period from 1941 to 2000, which has influenced the recent past of Yugoslavia, as well as post-Yugoslav societies.  Since its establishment Documenta contributes to the development of individual and social process of dealing with the past, in order to build sustainable peace in Croatia and the region by deepening the dialogue and initiating a public debate on public policies that encourage dealing with the past, collecting data, publishing research on war events, war crimes and violations of human rights, and monitoring war crimes trials at the local and regional level as a contribution to the improvement of court standards and practices in the war crimes trials.  Since 2006 Documenta is working on building and strengthening regional coalition of civil society organizations from post-Yugoslav countries, advocating the establishment of Regional Commission for establishing the facts upon conflicts in the region (RECOM).</cmd:history><cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext xml:lang="en">The establishment of Documenta – Centre for Dealing with the Past was an attempt to encourage the process of dealing with the past and establishing factual truth about the war and to contribute to shifting of the discussion from the level of dispute over facts (the number of killed people, etc.) towards a dialogue on interpretations.  The key reason for making this attempt was the silence about and falsification of war crimes and other war-related events in the period from 1941 to 2000, which has influenced the recent past of Yugoslavia, as well as post-Yugoslav societies.  The geographical scope of the work of Documenta covers Croatia, as well as Bosnia and Herzegovina, Serbia and Montenegro. </cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext><cmd:administrativeStructure xml:lang="en">Documenta’s  highest managing body is the Assembly, which is made up from all members of the organization and which meets once a year. The assembly adopts a report on organization’s work and elects members to the Managing Board, as well as new members of the organization.  Documenta’s Managing Board meets when needed, but at least twice a year. The Managing Board adopts acts needed for functioning of the organization and elects Documenta’s director.  Documenta’s Director is a person who is authorized to represent the organization and who leads and directs professional and other work on the implementation of organization’s program.</cmd:administrativeStructure><cmd:recordsManagmentAndCollectingPolicies xml:lang="en">The project “Unveiling Personal Memories on War and Detention” is intended to create a collection of video-recorded testimonies on a wide range of war experiences in Croatia. proposes the use of oral history as a method to collect and open up individual memories on past traumatic events from a wide range of perspectives, including those of minorities, victims, women, war veterans…  It is our contention that revealing and disseminating the variety of perspectives on how war affects an individual will contribute to a better understanding of what the circumstances are that can lead to the collapse of civil society.  The project aims to combine the method of collecting personal memories, with innovative ICT tools in order to make these sources accessible and searchable through the Internet for a wide range of audiences. The purpose is to record a set of 400 interviews and narratives on personal experiences on various wars and political violence in the period between 1941 and 1995 in Croatia.  The interviews will be transcribed, elaborated, translated and indexed, and an appropriate subset of the material will be stored on an open internet platform with direct access possibilities, enabling the editing, publication and streaming of interviews with advanced search options in the Croatian and English language.  Personal memories are recorded in the form of video-interview which will be accessible on an internet platform www.osobnasjecanja.hr and www.croatianmemories.org   According to available findings, material created during the nineties by of work of CSOs in Croatia, has not been settled or deposited and there is a danger that it will not be preserved. Awareness of the importance of this material is still not sufficiently developed, both within CSOs and beyond.  Through several projects, Documenta has begun a long-term process that should allow for complete records-created work of civil society to be permanently preserved as an integral part of social and historical heritage, available to future generations of students, researchers, public and all interested parties. Keeping this segment of the social and historical heritage is an integral process of democratization of Croatian society and one of the bases for the study of recent Croatian history.  Documenta recognizes the importance of documenting the most invisible part, but not less important activist work of CSOs. Documenta has subsequently published two manuals, organized a series of practical courses and roundtables on archiving to encourage civil society to understand the significance of the process of systematically classifying, cataloging and archiving material, with the aim of establishing a documentation center that would consolidate the archives of organizations for the protection of human rights.  Documenta’s archive as one of its holdings is in a possession of Antiwar Campaign Croatia (Antiratna kampanja Hrvatske, ARK/AWCC) archive, which contains documentation from the period 1990 -2006. Documentation is not in organized state, and one of the most important aims of Documenta’s archive is organization and digitization of the material. In the year 2011, 20 years was passing from the founding of AWCC. Documenta, together with activists of this network was engaged in the process of marking this anniversary. We organized two circles of conversation with actors of AWCC and a round table. We also searched through the whole documentation contained in the AWCC archive in Documenta, as well as archives held by other private holders of respective documentation. As a result of this project, a book Antiwar campaign 1990 – 2011. Untold history was published. Also as a part of marking 20th anniversary, on March 1-2 a regional conference “Legacy of Peace Initiatives” was organized in Zagreb.</cmd:recordsManagmentAndCollectingPolicies><cmd:archivalHoldings xml:lang="en">The online collection Unveiling Personal Memories on War and Detention; Collection of records of Croatian Civil Society organisations, including the Anti-War Campaign Croatia; </cmd:archivalHoldings><cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications xml:lang="en">Online customised search engine available for the collection Unveiling Personal Memories on War and Detention http://www.croatianmemories.org/en/video-search/</cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea><cmd:Level1><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level2><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level3><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level4><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection></cmd:Level4></cmd:Level3></cmd:Level2></cmd:Level1></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions></cmd:Components></cmd:CMD>