<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><cmd:CMD xmlns:cmd="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/ http://catalog.clarin.eu/ds/ComponentRegistry/rest/registry/1.1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934/xsd" CMDVersion="1.1"><cmd:Header><cmd:MdCreator>test</cmd:MdCreator><cmd:MdCreationDate xmlns:clariah="http://www.clariah.eu/" clariah:epoch="1737983582">2025-01-27</cmd:MdCreationDate><cmd:MdSelfLink>unl://5</cmd:MdSelfLink><cmd:MdProfile>clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934</cmd:MdProfile><cmd:MdCollectionDisplayName/></cmd:Header><cmd:Resources><cmd:ResourceProxyList/><cmd:JournalFileProxyList/><cmd:ResourceRelationList/><cmd:IsPartOfList/></cmd:Resources><cmd:Components><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions><cmd:status>under construction</cmd:status><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea><cmd:DREidentifier>DRE_CHI_005</cmd:DREidentifier><cmd:Names><cmd:authorisedForm>Fond za humanitarno pravo</cmd:authorisedForm><cmd:parallelForm>Humanitarian Law Center</cmd:parallelForm><cmd:otherForm>FHP; HLC; FDH;  Fondi për të Drejtën Humanitare; Фонд за хуманитарно право; </cmd:otherForm></cmd:Names></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea><cmd:city xml:lang="en">Belgrade</cmd:city><cmd:country xml:lang="en">Serbia</cmd:country><cmd:telephoneNumber>+381-11-3349-600; +381-11-3349-766; +381-11-3349-856; </cmd:telephoneNumber><cmd:faxNumber>+381-11-3232-460</cmd:faxNumber><cmd:email>office@hlc-rdc.org; archive@hlc-rdc.org</cmd:email><cmd:website>http://www.hlc-rdc.org/?lang=de</cmd:website><cmd:locationsAndAdresses><cmd:Adress>Dečanska 12</cmd:Adress></cmd:locationsAndAdresses></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea><cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea><cmd:history xml:lang="en">Humanitarian Law Center (HLC) was established in 1992 by human rights activist Nataša Kandić as a human rights non-governmental organisation that would document the human rights violations perpetrated on a massive scale across the former Yugoslavia, during the armed conflicts in Croatia, in Bosnia, and later in Kosovo. Since 1992 HLC has worked tirelessly to document war crimes and human rights abuses and support victims and their families in achieving justice. The HLC documentation was crucial for landmark cases at the ICTY such as Foča, a pivotal case in prosecution of wartime sexual violence. When the Kosovo war started, HLC established offices there and stayed in during the NATO bombing, even when the ICRC, OSCE and international media left, reporting from Kosovo. After the wars ended, HLC turned to transitional justice. It developed a model for representing victims in domestic war crime trials, enabling the families of victims from Bosnia, Croatia and Kosovo to come to trials in Serbia. Moreover, HLC has represented more than 1000 victims of human rights violations and war crimes in civil proceedings for compensation at courts in Serbia. HLC initiated the Kosovo Memory Book, a still ongoing project that documents every individual case of war-related death and disappearance in Kosovo between 1998 and 2000. Finally, HLC nurtures a regional approach to justice through RECOM – a civil society initiative to create an official regional truth commission to establish the facts about war crimes and human rights violations committed on the territory of the former Yugoslavia in the period between 1991 and 2001. HLC has developed numerous partnerships and it is a member of Coalition for RECOM, International Coalition of Sites of Conscience and Victim Support Europe</cmd:history><cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext xml:lang="en">Humanitarian Law Center has worked on documentation of war crimes and human rights violations since 1992. Over the years, the HLC has collected more than three million files related to the armed conflicts in the territory of the former Yugoslavia. The HLC Archive stores primary materials pertaining to mass human rights violations gathered since 1992 and more than 90% of the copies of the public archive of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia (ICTY). Among other items, the Archive contains documents from the war crimes trials held at domestic courts in Serbia and the region, media archive from the 1990s and ICTY materials, such as audio and video recordings and evidence presented at trials. The Archive is in to the continuous digitisation process. The HLC archives cover the geographical area of the former Yugoslavia, including the countries of Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Serbia and Montenegro.  </cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext><cmd:administrativeStructure xml:lang="en">The work of Humanitarian Law Center encompasses documentation, justice and memory. Humanitarian Law Center supports post-Yugoslav societies in promotion of the rule of law and acceptance of the legacy of mass human rights violations, and therefore in establishing the criminal responsibility of the perpetrators, serving justice, and preventing recurrence. Realisation of these goals in the region implies going through a comprehensive and multifaceted transitional justice process. First and foremost, victims of war crimes need to fulfil their right to justice, truth, and reparation. Second, this process encompasses bringing those responsible for the crimes to court and unravelling of the institutional and state structures that were instrumental in the systematic human rights violation of the 1990s wars. Finally, awareness of the crimes that took place and giving recognition to the victims in broader society is crucial so that such crimes do not happen again. Humanitarian Law Center is organised in three pillars and implements transitional justice program through them:      Documentation     Justice     Memory  1. Documentation  Humanitarian Law Center has worked on documentation of war crimes and human rights violations since 1992. Over the years, the HLC has collected more than three million files related to the armed conflicts in the territory of the former Yugoslavia. The HLC Archive stores primary materials pertaining to mass human rights violations gathered since 1992 and more than 90% of the copies of the public archive of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia (ICTY). Among other items, the Archive contains documents from the war crimes trials held at domestic courts in Serbia and the region, media archive from the 1990s and ICTY materials, such as audio and video recordings and evidence presented at trials. The Archive is in to the continuous digitisation process.  2. Justice  The judicial pillar of Humanitarian Law Center encompasses legal representation of victims of war crimes before Serbian courts, monitoring of all war crimes trials held in Serbia, representation of victims in compensation proceedings and filing legal complaints against perpetrators of war crimes to the War Crimes Prosecutor’s Office. It also includes publication of dossiers that highlight the complicity of high-ranking members of the army and police forces in war crimes and represent a call for vetting. Finally, the judicial pillar involves policy research and advocacy for judicial and institutional reforms to enable fulfilment of the right to justice for victims.  3. Memory  Humanitarian Law Center commemorates victims through various initiatives, including public debates, documentary films and digital memory activism on social media and through other digital memory practices. In addition to commemorating victims of war crimes and mass human rights violations during the 1990s wars, memorialisation program challenges and confronts the dominant revisionist narratives about the wars, provides informal education, disseminates the judicially determined facts about the wars in an engaging way, using different media formats. The program conducts policy-oriented research and analysis as well as commentary of official memory politics in the region.</cmd:administrativeStructure><cmd:recordsManagmentAndCollectingPolicies xml:lang="en">Primary material relating to mass human rights violations which were committed on the territory of the former Yugoslavia, and more than 90% of the copies of the Public Archive of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia (ICTY), have been stored in the Humanitarian Law Center’s (HLC) Archive.  The primary materials have been gathered during the research into war crimes and human rights violations that the HLC has been conducting since 1992. Besides this, the HLC has  acquired part of its archival materials from institutions with which it has cooperated  in the course of  the thirty years of its existence. Hence, the HLC’s Archive contains, among other items, a great number of documents from war crimes trials held in Serbia, Montenegro, Croatia, and Bosnia and Herzegovina, a media archive from the 1990’s, and audio and video recordings of ICTY trials, as well as documents which were presented as evidence in ICTY trials.</cmd:recordsManagmentAndCollectingPolicies><cmd:archivalHoldings xml:lang="en">The HLC’s Archive contains a total of 119,20 meters of printed documents, 39.126 CDs containing the ICTY Archive, and 1692 CDs and DVDs with various video materials – TV reports, films, footage from conferences, forums and meetings, and recordings of oral history interviews.   FUNDS:  FHP-SS-001 FUND:  Court documents  from trial of Albanians during the Slobodan Milošević era  FHP-SS-002  FUND:  Court documents, from trials of Serbian citizens for war crimes  FHP-OV-003 FUND:  Court documents  from trials of members of Vukovar Territorial Defence and the Leva Supoderica paramilitary unit for war crimes against prisoners of war  FHP-ZV-004 FUND:  Court files from trials of members of the paramilitary unit known as the „YELLOW WASPS“  for crimes against civilians in Zvornik  FHP-SC-005 FUND: Court files from trials of members of the “Scorpions” paramilitary unit for crimes against civilians in Srebrenica  FHP-LR-006 FUND: Court documents, from trials of members of Military Police of the Croatian Army for Crimes Committed in the Military Prison  FHP-SB-007  FUND: Court documents from trial of members of the Republic of Srpska Army for Crimes against Civilians in Srebrenica  FHP-SJ-008  FUND:  Court documents from trial of members of the „Avengers“ paramilitary formation for the abduction and murder of Muslims from Sjeverin in Serbia   FHP-ST-009  FUND: Court documents from trial of soldiers of the Republic of Srpska Army for the abduction and murder of civilians from the train in Štrpci  FHP-PD-010 FUND: Court documents from trials of members of the “Scorpions“ paramilitary unit for crimes against civilians in Podujevo  FHP-PR-011 FUND: Police repression in Serbia and Kosovo SUBFUND: FHP-PR-011-1 Otpor  FHP-NP-012 FUND: Right to property, and claims for restoration of displaced persons’ tenancy rights  FHP-EX-014 FUND: Exhumations in Serbia and Kosovo  FHP-SN-015 FUND:  Documents pertinent to the position of minorities and to human rights violations on the territory of Sandžak  FHP-SP-016 FUND: Representation of political parties and presidential candidates in electronic and printed media in Serbia  FHP-KF-017 FUND: Humanitarian Law Center Organized Conferences  FHP-DJ-021 FUND: Transcripts from the trial for the assassination of the Prime Minister of the Republic of Serbia, Dr. Zoran Đinđić  FHP-SH-025 FUND: Court documents, from trials of Croat citizens for war crimes  FHP-RO-026  FUND: Roma – incident reports, various cases of assaults on Roma, their right to residence and discrimination against, eviction of Roma, their right to life and discrimination against, deportation of Roma from the Federal Republic of Germany, CAT (Convention Against Torture)  FHP-LV-0027 FUND:  Court files, from trials of members of paramilitary formations and JNA  soldiers, for Crimes Committed Against Civilians in Lovas  FHP-CU-028 FUND:  Court files from trials of members of the 177th Platoon of the Peć Military Territorial Detachment of the Yugoslav Army for war crimes against prisoners of war in the village of Ćuška in Kosovo  FHP-BY-029 FUND:  Court files from the trial of members of the Serbian Ministry of the Interior, for the war crime against prisoners of war in Petrovo selo, Serbia  FHP-OR-030 FUND: A Time When People Spoke – Echoes and Reactions  FHP-IF-031 FUND: Research by the Humanitarian Law Center into War Propaganda in the Printed Media</cmd:archivalHoldings><cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications xml:lang="en">Online description of archival holdings organised per fonds avalaible at http://www.hlc-rdc.org/?page_id=17468&amp;lang=de</cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea><cmd:Level1><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:referencecode>FHP-SS-002</cmd:referencecode><cmd:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1993-2006</cmd:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation><cmd:levelOfDescription>Eng</cmd:levelOfDescription><cmd:extentAndMedium xml:lang="en">11 archival boxes </cmd:extentAndMedium><cmd:titles><cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>Sudski spisi, sa suđenja Srbima za ratne zločine</cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle><cmd:parallelFormsOfTitles>Court documents, from trials of Serbian citizens for war crimes; Materiale gjyqësore nga gjykimet e shtetasve të Serbisë për krime të luftës; </cmd:parallelFormsOfTitles></cmd:titles></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea><cmd:scopeAndContent xml:lang="en">The fonds contains documents from trials of members of Serb and Croat national communities for war crimes committed on the territory of the former Yugoslavia, which were monitored by researchers and attorneys from the HLC. The trials were conducted on the territory of Serbia, Kosovo, Croatia, and Bosnia and Herzegovina. The fonds covers the period from 1991 to the present. The fonds contains court documents (indictments, verdicts, appeals, decisions, records of examinations of the accused, transcripts of trials, records from witness examinations, official notes, trial reports, memoranda, motions for termination of detention, petitions, certificates, powers of attorney), and newspaper articles and accompanying documents.</cmd:scopeAndContent><cmd:accruals>Further accruals are expected</cmd:accruals><cmd:systemOfArrangement xml:lang="en">Boxes are organized geographically in accordance with the location of the court (alphabetically), and each case is organized chronologically (by date). Box no. 1      Trials of Croats and Serbs for war crimes committed on the territory of the former Yugoslavia. Trials conducted on the territory of Croatia before the District Courts in Varaždin, Vukovar, Zagreb, Zadar, Karlovci, Osijek, Požega, Split and Šibenik. A total of 31 cases.  Box no. 2      Trials of Croats and Serbs for war crimes committed on the territory of the former Yugoslavia. Trials conducted on the territory of Croatia, Serbia and Kosovo,  before the County Court in Vukovar (Croatia), the Municipal Court in Split (Croatia), the County Court in Zagreb (Croatia), the Supreme Court of Croatia, the District Court in Belgrade (Serbia), the District Court in Gnjilane (Kosovo) and the District Court in Priština (Kosovo). A total of 5 cases.  Box no. 3      Trial of Dragan Nikolić from Gnjilane, charged with the crime of killing, together with a group of co-perpetrators,  a person of Albanian nationality. The trial was conducted before the District Court in Gnjilane (Kosovo), the District Court in Priština (Kosovo) and the Supreme Court of Kosovo. A total of 1 case (79 documents).  Box no. 4      Trials of Serbs for war crimes committed on the territory of Kosovo conducted before the District Court in Mitrovica (Kosovo). A total of 4 cases.  Box no. 5      Trials of Serbs for war crimes committed on the territory of Kosovo conducted before the District Court in Mitrovica, District Court in Peć, District Court in Prizren, and District Court in Priština (Kosovo). A total of 10 cases.  Box no. 6      Trials of Serbs for war crimes and other criminal offences conducted before the District Court in Belgrade, the Military Court in Belgrade, and the Supreme Military Court (Serbia). A total of 10 cases.  Box no. 7      Miscellaneous documents (with reference to espionage, disclosure of a military secret, murder, enforced disappearances of soldiers, inappropriate use of weapons issued to soldiers, army desertion, preventing an official  discharge  duties), relating to the Municipal Court in Kragujevac, District Court in Kraljevo, District Court in Leskovac, Military Court in Niš, and Military Court in Novi Sad. A total of 13 cases.  Box no. 8      Miscellaneous documents (with reference to terrorism, unauthorized possession of weapons, criminal offence of murder, unauthorized crossing of the border, war crimes trial – the  “Yellow Wasps” Case against the accused, Duško and Vojin Vučković). District Court in Smederevo, District Court in Užice, District Court in Požarevac, District Court in Prokuplje, District Court in Sremska Mitrovica, District Court in Šabac. A total of 6 cases.  Box no. 9      Trials of Serbs for war crimes and other criminal offences conducted before the District Court in Murska Subota (Slovenia), District Court in Novi Pazar (Serbia), Primary Court in Nikšić (Montenegro), Primary Court in Cetinje (Montenegro), District Court in Banja Luka, Higher Court in Zenica, Cantonal Court in Sarajevo (Bosnia and Herzegovina), District Military Court in Tuzla, Higher Court in Podgorica. A total of 14 cases.  Box no. 10      Separate trial of Saša Radak, who (as a member of a volunteer unit within the then Yugoslav Peoples’ Army) in violation of international humanitarian law killed two hundred persons at the Ovčara Farm, thus committing a war crime against prisoners of war. The trial was conducted before the District Court in Belgrade War Crimes Chamber (Serbia). A total of 1 case (9 documents).  Box no. 11      The trial of Anđelko Kolašinac et al. for a war crime against the civilian population, conducted before the District Court in Prizren (Kosovo). A total of 1 case (34 documents).</cmd:systemOfArrangement></cmd:contentAndStructureArea><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea><cmd:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial xml:lang="en">Serbian; Croatian; Albanian; </cmd:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial></cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea><cmd:languageOfDescription>Eng</cmd:languageOfDescription><cmd:scriptOfDescription>Lat</cmd:scriptOfDescription><cmd:sources>Humanitarian Law Centre fonds description http://www.hlc-rdc.org/?p=21404&amp;lang=de</cmd:sources><cmd:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE guidelines</cmd:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines><cmd:datesOfDescription>2025-01-27</cmd:datesOfDescription></cmd:descriptionControlArea></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level2><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level3><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection><cmd:Level4><cmd:Collection><cmd:identificationArea><cmd:titles/></cmd:identificationArea><cmd:contextArea/><cmd:contentAndStructureArea/><cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/><cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/><cmd:notes/><cmd:descriptionControlArea/></cmd:Collection></cmd:Level4></cmd:Level3></cmd:Level2></cmd:Level1></cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions></cmd:Components></cmd:CMD>