<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cmd:CMD xmlns:cmd="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/ http://catalog.clarin.eu/ds/ComponentRegistry/rest/registry/1.1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934/xsd"
    CMDVersion="1.1">
    <cmd:Header>
        <cmd:MdCreator>test</cmd:MdCreator>
        <cmd:MdCreationDate xmlns:clariah="http://www.clariah.eu/" clariah:epoch="1737974570"
            >2025-01-27</cmd:MdCreationDate>
        <cmd:MdSelfLink>unl://4</cmd:MdSelfLink>
        <cmd:MdProfile>clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934</cmd:MdProfile>
        <cmd:MdCollectionDisplayName/>
    </cmd:Header>
    <cmd:Resources>
        <cmd:ResourceProxyList/>
        <cmd:JournalFileProxyList/>
        <cmd:ResourceRelationList/>
        <cmd:IsPartOfList/>
    </cmd:Resources>
    <cmd:Components>
        <cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions>
            <cmd:status>under construction</cmd:status>
            <cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea>
                <cmd:DREidentifier>DRE_CHI_004</cmd:DREidentifier>
                <cmd:typeOfInstitution>International Organisation</cmd:typeOfInstitution>
                <cmd:Names>
                    <cmd:authorisedForm>United Nations International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals</cmd:authorisedForm>
                    <cmd:parallelForm>Nations Unies Mécanisme international appelé à exercer les fonctions résiduelles des Tribunaux pénaux</cmd:parallelForm>
                    <cmd:otherForm>UN IRMCT; Ujedinjene nacije Međunarodni rezidualni mehanizam za krivične sudove</cmd:otherForm>
                </cmd:Names>
            </cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea>
            <cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea>
                <cmd:address>Churchillplein 1</cmd:address>
                <cmd:city xml:lang="en">The Hague</cmd:city>
                <cmd:regionProvince xml:lang="en">Zuid Holland</cmd:regionProvince>
                <cmd:country xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</cmd:country>
                <cmd:telephoneNumber>0031 (0)70 512 5037</cmd:telephoneNumber>
                <cmd:email>marshague@un.org</cmd:email>
                <cmd:website>https://www.irmct.org/en</cmd:website>
            </cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea>
            <cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea>
                <cmd:history xml:lang="en">On 22 December 2010,  the UN SC Resolution 1566 established  the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (the IRMCT), a temporary body created to carry out a number of essential functions of the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda (ICTR) and the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) after the completion of their respective mandates. The MICT has two branches covering the residual functions of the respective tribunals: The ICTY branch in The Hague and the ICTR branch in Arusha, Tanzania. The ICTY branch of the IRMCT commenced its operations on 01 July 2013 and continued parallel existence with the ICTY until the closure of the ICTY on 31 December 2017. The IRMCT is tasked with continuing the “jurisdiction, rights and obligations and essential functions” (UNSC Resolution 1966) of the ICTY and maintaining its legacy. This includes the ad hoc functions, such as the completion of the remaining appellate proceedings, possible retrials or review proceedings and trials for contempt of court and false testimony. Continuing functions of the IRMCT include the following: Protection of victims and witnesses, supervision of enforcement of sentences, assistance to national jurisdictions, as well as preservation and management of the ICTY archive. </cmd:history>
                <cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext xml:lang="en">The Hague branch of the IRMCT is a custodian of the archives created during the operation of the  International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY), as well as the archived records created during in the course of the judicial operations of the IRMCT itself. While it is located in the seat of the IRMCT and the former seat of the ICTY, in The Netherlands, significant part of the archives cover the geographical area of the former Yugoslavia, including the countries of Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, North Macedonia, Serbia and Montenegro.  </cmd:geographicalAndCulturalContext>
                <cmd:mandatesOrSourcesOfAuthority xml:lang="en">United Nations Security Council
                    Resolution 1566 (2010)</cmd:mandatesOrSourcesOfAuthority>
                <cmd:administrativeStructure xml:lang="en">The Mechanism operates across two branches: one branch in Arusha, United Republic of Tanzania, and the other in The Hague, the Netherlands.  The Mechanism consists of a single set of Principals: a President, a Prosecutor, and a Registrar. The Principals have responsibility over both branches of the Mechanism and oversee each of the three organs, respectively:  Chambers  Article 4 of the Statute provides that the Chambers shall comprise a Trial Chamber for each branch of the Mechanism and an Appeals Chamber common to both branches of the Mechanism. A roster of 25 independent Judges, including the President, adjudicate proceedings at both branches of the Mechanism. In so far as possible, and so as to maximize efficiency, Judges work remotely and are only required to be at either branch as necessary and at the request of the President. The Judges are supported by Chambers staff at both branches. The Office of the Prosecutor  The Office of the Prosecutor is responsible for the investigation and prosecution of persons covered by Article 1 of the Statute of the Mechanism. The Registry  The Registrar heads the Registry, which provides administrative, legal, policy and diplomatic support services to all organs in both branches of the Mechanism.  Each Organ maintains a roster of qualified potential staff to enable it to recruit additional staff rapidly as may be required to perform its functions. As of October 2016, the Mechanism has Judges coming from 24 countries and staff representing 65 nationalities.  In addition, a roster of Defence Counsel is maintained to ensure that the highest standards of fair trial rights are upheld. Rule 43 of the Mechanism’s Rules of Procedure and Evidence provide that “[w]henever the interests of justice so demand, Defence Counsel S1shall be assigned to suspects or accused who lack the means to remunerate such Counsel”. The Registry administers the Mechanism’s legal aid system, which provides support to defence teams. Detention and the IRMCT+S2  The Mechanism maintains two detention facilities at its respective branches, which house detainees subject to its jurisdiction. Both are operated in line with international standards for treatment of detainees.</cmd:administrativeStructure>
                <cmd:buildings xml:lang="en">Churchillplein 1, protected building (temporary accomodation) </cmd:buildings>
                <cmd:archivalHoldings xml:lang="en">The International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals is custodian to the archives created during the operation of the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (in The Hague, The Netherlands); the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda (in Arusha, Tanzania); and the IInternational Residual mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (in both branches). </cmd:archivalHoldings>
                <cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications xml:lang="en">Online catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/search/simple); Unified Court Records Database (UCR) User Help (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmd:findingAidsGuidesPublications>
            </cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea>
            <cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsControlArea/>
            <cmd:Level1>
                <cmd:Collection>
                    <cmd:identificationArea>
                        <cmd:titles>
                            <cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle/>
                        </cmd:titles>
                    </cmd:identificationArea>
                    <cmd:contextArea/>
                    <cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                        <cmd:scopeAndContent/>
                    </cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                    <cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/>
                    <cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/>
                    <cmd:notes/>
                    <cmd:descriptionControlArea/>
                </cmd:Collection>
                <cmd:Level2>
                    <cmd:Collection>
                        <cmd:identificationArea>
                            <cmd:titles>
                                <cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle/>
                            </cmd:titles>
                        </cmd:identificationArea>
                        <cmd:contextArea/>
                        <cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmd:scopeAndContent/>
                        </cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                        <cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/>
                        <cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/>
                        <cmd:notes/>
                        <cmd:descriptionControlArea/>
                    </cmd:Collection>
                    <cmd:Level3>
                        <cmd:Collection>
                            <cmd:identificationArea>
                                <cmd:titles>
                                    <cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>/</cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                                </cmd:titles>
                            </cmd:identificationArea>
                            <cmd:contextArea/>
                            <cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                                <cmd:scopeAndContent/>
                            </cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/>
                            <cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/>
                            <cmd:notes/>
                            <cmd:descriptionControlArea/>
                        </cmd:Collection>
                        <cmd:Level4>
                            <cmd:Collection>
                                <cmd:identificationArea>
                                    <cmd:titles>
                                        <cmd:AuthorizedFormOfTitle/>
                                    </cmd:titles>
                                </cmd:identificationArea>
                                <cmd:contextArea/>
                                <cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                                    <cmd:scopeAndContent/>
                                </cmd:contentAndStructureArea>
                                <cmd:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/>
                                <cmd:alliedMaterialsArea/>
                                <cmd:notes/>
                                <cmd:descriptionControlArea/>
                            </cmd:Collection>
                        </cmd:Level4>
                    </cmd:Level3>
                </cmd:Level2>
            </cmd:Level1>
        </cmd:CollectionHoldingInstitutions>
    </cmd:Components>
</cmd:CMD>
