<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cmd:CMD xmlns:cmd="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1"
    xmlns:cmdp="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" CMDVersion="1.2"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1 https://infra.clarin.eu/CMDI/1.x/xsd/cmd-envelop.xsd http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934 https://catalog.clarin.eu/ds/ComponentRegistry/rest/registry/1.1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934/1.2/xsd">
    <cmd:Header>
        <cmd:MdCreator>test</cmd:MdCreator>
        <cmd:MdCreationDate xmlns:clariah="http://www.clariah.eu/" clariah:epoch="1738672244"
            >2025-02-04</cmd:MdCreationDate>
        <cmd:MdSelfLink>unl://4</cmd:MdSelfLink>
        <cmd:MdProfile>clarin.eu:cr1:p_1721373443934</cmd:MdProfile>
        <cmd:MdCollectionDisplayName/>
    </cmd:Header>
    <cmd:Resources>
        <cmd:ResourceProxyList/>
        <cmd:JournalFileProxyList/>
        <cmd:ResourceRelationList/>
    </cmd:Resources>
    <cmd:Components>
        <cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutions>
            <cmdp:status>under construction</cmdp:status>
            <cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea>
                <cmdp:DREidentifier>DRE_CHI_004</cmdp:DREidentifier>
                <cmdp:typeOfInstitution>International Organisation</cmdp:typeOfInstitution>
                <cmdp:Names>
                    <cmdp:authorisedForm>United Nations International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals</cmdp:authorisedForm>
                    <cmdp:parallelForm>Nations Unies Mécanisme international appelé à exercer les fonctions résiduelles des Tribunaux pénaux</cmdp:parallelForm>
                    <cmdp:otherForm>UN IRMCT; Ujedinjene nacije Međunarodni rezidualni mehanizam za krivične sudove</cmdp:otherForm>
                </cmdp:Names>
            </cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsIdentityArea>
            <cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea>
                <cmdp:address>Churchillplein 1</cmdp:address>
                <cmdp:city xml:lang="en">The Hague</cmdp:city>
                <cmdp:regionProvince xml:lang="en">Zuid Holland</cmdp:regionProvince>
                <cmdp:country xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</cmdp:country>
                <cmdp:telephoneNumber>0031 (0)70 512 5037</cmdp:telephoneNumber>
                <cmdp:email>marshague@un.org</cmdp:email>
                <cmdp:website>https://www.irmct.org/en</cmdp:website>
            </cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsContactArea>
            <cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea>
                <cmdp:history xml:lang="en">On 22 December 2010,  the UN SC Resolution 1566 established  the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (the IRMCT), a temporary body created to carry out a number of essential functions of the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda (ICTR) and the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY) after the completion of their respective mandates. The MICT has two branches covering the residual functions of the respective tribunals: The ICTY branch in The Hague and the ICTR branch in Arusha, Tanzania. The ICTY branch of the IRMCT commenced its operations on 01 July 2013 and continued parallel existence with the ICTY until the closure of the ICTY on 31 December 2017. The IRMCT is tasked with continuing the “jurisdiction, rights and obligations and essential functions” (UNSC Resolution 1966) of the ICTY and maintaining its legacy. This includes the ad hoc functions, such as the completion of the remaining appellate proceedings, possible retrials or review proceedings and trials for contempt of court and false testimony. Continuing functions of the IRMCT include the following: Protection of victims and witnesses, supervision of enforcement of sentences, assistance to national jurisdictions, as well as preservation and management of the ICTY archive. </cmdp:history>
                <cmdp:geographicalAndCulturalContext xml:lang="en">The Hague branch of the IRMCT is a custodian of the archives created during the operation of the  International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY), as well as the archived records created during in the course of the judicial operations of the IRMCT itself. While it is located in the seat of the IRMCT and the former seat of the ICTY, in The Netherlands, significant part of the archives cover the geographical area of the former Yugoslavia, including the countries of Croatia, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, North Macedonia, Serbia and Montenegro.  </cmdp:geographicalAndCulturalContext>
                <cmdp:mandatesOrSourcesOfAuthority xml:lang="en">United Nations Security Council                    Resolution 1566 (2010)</cmdp:mandatesOrSourcesOfAuthority>
                <cmdp:administrativeStructure xml:lang="en">The Mechanism operates across two branches: one branch in Arusha, United Republic of Tanzania, and the other in The Hague, the Netherlands.  The Mechanism consists of a single set of Principals: a President, a Prosecutor, and a Registrar. The Principals have responsibility over both branches of the Mechanism and oversee each of the three organs, respectively:  Chambers  Article 4 of the Statute provides that the Chambers shall comprise a Trial Chamber for each branch of the Mechanism and an Appeals Chamber common to both branches of the Mechanism. A roster of 25 independent Judges, including the President, adjudicate proceedings at both branches of the Mechanism. In so far as possible, and so as to maximize efficiency, Judges work remotely and are only required to be at either branch as necessary and at the request of the President. The Judges are supported by Chambers staff at both branches. The Office of the Prosecutor  The Office of the Prosecutor is responsible for the investigation and prosecution of persons covered by Article 1 of the Statute of the Mechanism. The Registry  The Registrar heads the Registry, which provides administrative, legal, policy and diplomatic support services to all organs in both branches of the Mechanism.  Each Organ maintains a roster of qualified potential staff to enable it to recruit additional staff rapidly as may be required to perform its functions. As of October 2016, the Mechanism has Judges coming from 24 countries and staff representing 65 nationalities.  In addition, a roster of Defence Counsel is maintained to ensure that the highest standards of fair trial rights are upheld. Rule 43 of the Mechanism’s Rules of Procedure and Evidence provide that “[w]henever the interests of justice so demand, Defence Counsel S1shall be assigned to suspects or accused who lack the means to remunerate such Counsel”. The Registry administers the Mechanism’s legal aid system, which provides support to defence teams. Detention and the IRMCT+S2  The Mechanism maintains two detention facilities at its respective branches, which house detainees subject to its jurisdiction. Both are operated in line with international standards for treatment of detainees.</cmdp:administrativeStructure>
                <cmdp:buildings xml:lang="en">Churchillplein 1, protected building (temporary accomodation) </cmdp:buildings>
                <cmdp:archivalHoldings xml:lang="en">The International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals is custodian to the archives created during the operation of the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (in The Hague, The Netherlands); the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda (in Arusha, Tanzania); and the IInternational Residual mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (in both branches). </cmdp:archivalHoldings>
                <cmdp:findingAidsGuidesPublications xml:lang="en">Online catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/search/simple); Unified Court Records Database (UCR) User Help (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAidsGuidesPublications>
            </cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsDescriptionArea>
            <cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutionsControlArea/>
            <cmdp:Level1>
                <cmdp:Collection>
                    <cmdp:identificationArea>
                        <cmdp:referencecode>ICTY</cmdp:referencecode>
                        <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1993</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                        <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>2017</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                        <cmdp:levelOfDescription>Fonds</cmdp:levelOfDescription>
                        <cmdp:extentAndMedium xml:lang="en">2,500 linear metres of physical records; 2 PB of digital records</cmdp:extentAndMedium>
                        <cmdp:titles>
                            <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia (ICTY)</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                            <cmdp:parallelFormsOfTitles>Tribunal pénal international pour l’ex-Yougoslavie</cmdp:parallelFormsOfTitles>
                            <cmdp:parallelFormsOfTitles>Međunarodni krivični sud za bivšu Jugoslaviju </cmdp:parallelFormsOfTitles>
                        </cmdp:titles>
                    </cmdp:identificationArea>
                    <cmdp:contextArea/>
                    <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                        <cmdp:scopeAndContent xml:lang="en">The fonds consists of documents, photographs,transctripts, video-recordings, electronic records and physical artefacts created, obtained and used in the course of the operation of the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslaiva (ICTY), between its inception in 1993 and its closure in 2017. The fonds include the records of three ICTY organs: the Chambers, the Office of the Prosecutor and the Registry, and document various aspects of the ICTY's operations. The fonds is divided into two broad categories, judicial records and non-judicial records. </cmdp:scopeAndContent>
                        <cmdp:accruals>No further accruals are expected</cmdp:accruals>
                        <cmdp:systemOfArrangement xml:lang="en">"The records of the ICTY fonds are divided into two broad categories: judicial case records and non-judicial records.   Judicial case records (ICTY/JCR) are arranged in the catalogue by case, and then by the four main series of records generated during a case: filings, exhibits, transcripts, and audiovisual recordings of proceedings.   Non-judicial records are arranged by function, following the ICTY retention schedule. The non-judicial records are divided into (1) records related to the judicial process, but which are not part of the case records, including functions carried out by the Office of the Prosecutor (OTP), and (2) administrative records.   Records related to the judicial process but not part of the case records consist of:  ICTY/JPM: Judicial proceedings management  ICTY/PTP: Pre-trial proceedings management  ICTY/TPM: Trial proceedings management  ICTY/RPM: Review proceedings management  ICTY/APM: Appeal proceedings management  ICTY/PFJ: Post-final-judgement proceedings management  ICTY/CAS: Court administration and support  ICTY/DEM: Detention management  ICTY/EAC: Expert and amicus curiae administration  ICTY/JRM: Judicial records management  ICTY/LSM: Language services management  ICTY/SEE: Sentence enforcement  ICTY/WAS: Witness assistance, support and protection  ICTY/DTA: Defence Team administration  ICTY/DET: Defence Team assistance  ICTY/FAM: Financial aid management  ICTY/INV: Investigation management  ICTY/IND: ICTY indictment management  ICTY/ART: Arrest and transfer  ICTY/PPD: Prosecution policy and procedure development  ICTY/PPT: Prosecution – pre-trial proceedings  ICTY/PTR: Prosecution – trail proceedings  ICTY/PRP: Prosecution – review proceedings  ICTY/PAP: Prosecution – appeal proceedings +I1 ICTY/CRS: Case referral and support  ICTY/FUT: Fugitive tracking  ICTY/INM: Information management  ICTY/INS: Information support  ICTY/REA: Research and analysis  ICTY/FRM: Request for Assistance (RFA) management     Administrative records consist of:  ICTY/AUM: Audit management  ICTY/BUD: Budget management  ICTY/FIM: Finance management  ICTY/HRM: Human resources management  ICTY/ICT: Information and Communications Technology (ICT) management  ICTY/IMA: Insurance management  ICTY/MSM: Mail services management  ICTY/PRM: Premises management  ICTY/PCM: Procurement management  ICTY/PMA: Property management  ICTY/SSM: Security management  ICTY/TRM: Travel management  ICTY/ERM: External relations management  ICTY/OPM: Outreach Programme management  ICTY/PIC: Public information management  ICTY/GOV: Governance  ICTY/EOR: ICTY Executive Offices records  ICTY/RMA: Records management  ICTY/AMA: Archives management     In addition, there are five series of Special Collections which consists of:  ICTY/COL/1: ICTY Official Photograph Collection  ICTY/COL/2: ICTY Oral history project  ICTY/COL/3: ICTY Staff Union ephemera  ICTY/COL/4: ICTY Ephemera Collection  ICTY/COL/5: ICTY Legacy Dialogues records "</cmdp:systemOfArrangement>
                    </cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                    <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                        <cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess xml:lang="en">Access to records is subject to the Access Policy for the Records held by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (MICT/17/Rev.1) https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf</cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Latin; Serbian Cyrilic; Macedonian
                            Cyrilic; </cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Bosnian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Croatian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Serbian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Macedonian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Albanian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>French</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                        <cmdp:findingAids xml:lang="en">Catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/results); United Court Records Databaase User Guide (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAids>
                    </cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                    <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                        <cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies xml:lang="en">Public records can be found in the Unified Court Records database via the ICTY and IRMCT websites. </cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>
                    </cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                    <cmdp:notes/>
                    <cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                        <cmdp:institutionIdentfier>DRE author</cmdp:institutionIdentfier>
                        <cmdp:languageOfDescription xml:lang="en">English</cmdp:languageOfDescription>
                        <cmdp:scriptOfDescription xml:lang="en">Latin</cmdp:scriptOfDescription>
                        <cmdp:sources>www.icty.org; </cmdp:sources>
                        <cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE Guidelines</cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>
                        <cmdp:datesOfDescription>2025-02-04</cmdp:datesOfDescription>
                    </cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                    <cmdp:Relationship/>
                </cmdp:Collection>
                <cmdp:Level2>
                    <cmdp:Collection>
                        <cmdp:identificationArea>
                            <cmdp:referencecode>ICTY/ JCR</cmdp:referencecode>
                            <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1993</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                            <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>2017</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                            <cmdp:levelOfDescription>Sub-Fonds</cmdp:levelOfDescription>
                            <cmdp:titles>
                                <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>ICTY judicial case records</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                            </cmdp:titles>
                        </cmdp:identificationArea>
                        <cmdp:contextArea/>
                        <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmdp:scopeAndContent xml:lang="en">The sub-fonds contains judicial case records for ICTY cases. The ICTY's Office of the Prosecutor (OTP) issued its first indictment in November 1994. Between then and 2004, when the Security Council mandated the end of investigations as part of the ICTY's completion strategy, the OTP issued indictments against 161 individuals for crimes allegedly committed during the wars in Croatia (1991-1995), Bosnia and Herzegovina (1992-1995), Kosovo (1999) and North Macedonia (2001). In addition to the individuals from these countries, a number of people from Federal Republic of Yugoslavia (which comprised Serbia and Montenegro) were indicted for crimes allegedly committed in Croatia, BiH and Kosovo. In addition to the records related to the judicial porceedings in cases against individuals accused of waar crimes, the sub-fonds includes the records of judicial proceedings in cases against individuals accused of contempt of court.  </cmdp:scopeAndContent>
                            <cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation xml:lang="en">Permanent retention /?/</cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>
                            <cmdp:accruals>No further accruals are expected</cmdp:accruals>
                            <cmdp:systemOfArrangement xml:lang="en">"he records are arranged by case and usually consist of:  1. filings – records related to the case which were submitted by a Chamber, Judge, Party or Non-Party (“Submitting Party”) and entered in the Case File by the Court Records Office  2. exhibits – records formally admitted into evidence by a Chamber  3. transcripts – verbatim, written records of court hearings or other proceedings before the Tribunal  4. audiovisual recordings of court hearings or other proceedings  There is a catalogue entry for each of these types of records for each case. However, not all of these types of records were created for every case. Where no such records were created for the case in question, the relevant catalogue entry will note this.  In addition to the Case File, a separate file was kept for correspondence related to the case (addressed to/from the Chamber, a Judge, a Party or a Non-Party) that was not submitted for filing or annexed to a filing as supporting material (""Correspondence File""). This correspondence was not part of the case record, but was maintained separately by the Court Management and Support Services Section."</cmdp:systemOfArrangement>
                        </cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                        <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                            <cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess xml:lang="en">Access to records is subject to the Access Policy for the Records held by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (MICT/17/Rev.1) (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf) https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf</cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>French</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Bosnian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Croatian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Serbian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Macedonian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Albanian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Dutch</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Spanish</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Norwegian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English Latin; French Latin; Bosnian/
                                Croatian Latin; Serbian Cyrilic; Macedonian Cyrilic; Albanian Latin; </cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                            <cmdp:findingAids xml:lang="en">Catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/results); United Court Records Databaase User Guide (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAids>
                        </cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                        <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                            <cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies xml:lang="en">Public records can be found in the Unified Court Records database via the ICTY and IRMCT websites. </cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>
                            <cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription xml:lang="en">For judicial case correspondence files, see ICTY/CAS/8</cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>
                        </cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                        <cmdp:notes/>
                        <cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                            <cmdp:institutionIdentfier>DRE author</cmdp:institutionIdentfier>
                            <cmdp:languageOfDescription xml:lang="en">English</cmdp:languageOfDescription>
                            <cmdp:scriptOfDescription xml:lang="en">Latin</cmdp:scriptOfDescription>
                            <cmdp:sources>www.icty.org; </cmdp:sources>
                            <cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE Guidelines</cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>
                            <cmdp:datesOfDescription>2025-02-04</cmdp:datesOfDescription>
                        </cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                        <cmdp:Relationship/>
                    </cmdp:Collection>
                    <cmdp:Level3>
                        <cmdp:Collection>
                            <cmdp:identificationArea>
                                <cmdp:referencecode>ICTY/ JCR/18</cmdp:referencecode>
                                <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1995</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                                <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1998</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                                <cmdp:levelOfDescription>Sub-sub-fonds</cmdp:levelOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:extentAndMedium xml:lang="en">1.6 linear metres of physical records; 91 digital items</cmdp:extentAndMedium>
                                <cmdp:titles>
                                    <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić and Veselin Šljivančanin (IT-95-13)</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                                </cmdp:titles>
                            </cmdp:identificationArea>
                            <cmdp:contextArea/>
                            <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                                <cmdp:scopeAndContent xml:lang="en">The sub-sub-fonds contains judicial case records for the Mrkšić et al. case (IT-95-13). Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić, Veselin Šljivančanin were initially indicted in November 1995 and charged with Crimes against humanity, Grave breaches of the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and Violations of laws or customs of war for crimes allegedlly committed in Vukovar, Croatia in November of 1991. In April 1996, the indictment was amended to include the fourth accused, Slavko Dokmanović. In June 1997, Dokmanović was arrested and transferred to the ICTY and the proceedings against his were severed into a separate case. The sub-sub-fonds It includes records of pre-trial proceedings, 30 October 1995 - 9 December 1998. See also related records.  </cmdp:scopeAndContent>
                                <cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation xml:lang="en">Permanent retention /?/</cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>
                                <cmdp:accruals>No further accruals are expected</cmdp:accruals>
                                <cmdp:systemOfArrangement xml:lang="en">"The records consist of:  ICTY/JCR/18/1: Filings  ICTY/JCR/18/2: Exhibits  ICTY/JCR/18/3: Transcripts  ICTY/JCR/18/4: Audiovisual recordings of court proceedings"</cmdp:systemOfArrangement>
                            </cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                                <cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess xml:lang="en">Access to records is subject to the Access Policy for the Records held by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (MICT/17/Rev.1) https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf</cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>French</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Croatian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Serbian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Bosnian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:findingAids xml:lang="en">Catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/results); United Court Records Databaase User Guide (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAids>
                            </cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                            <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                                <cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies xml:lang="en">Public records can be found in the Unified Court Records database via the ICTY and IRMCT websites. </cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>
                                <cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription xml:lang="en">"1) For details about the case, including the charges against the accused, see the Case Information Sheet 2) For the Mrkšić et al. case correspondence files, see ICTY/CAS/8 3) In 2002 the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13) became Mrkšić et al. (IT-95-13/1). For the Mrkšić et al. case, see ICTY/JCR/19 4) Slavko Dokmanović was originally indicted in the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13). In 1997 Dokmanović was separated to the Dokmanović case (IT-95-13a). For the Dokmanović case, see ICTY/JCR/20 5) For proceedings before the Mechanism in the Mrkšić et al. case, see IRMCT/JCR/94"</cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                            <cmdp:notes/>
                            <cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                                <cmdp:institutionIdentfier>DRE author</cmdp:institutionIdentfier>
                                <cmdp:languageOfDescription xml:lang="en">English</cmdp:languageOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:scriptOfDescription xml:lang="en">Latin</cmdp:scriptOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:sources>UN IRMCT Archive Catalogue; UN ICTY, Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13-I), Indictment, 07 Nov 1995;  UN ICTY, Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13a-I), Indictment, 01 Apr 1996; UN ICTY, "Vukovar Hospital", Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13/1), Case Info Sheet.  </cmdp:sources>
                                <cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE Guidelines</cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>
                                <cmdp:datesOfDescription>2025-02-04</cmdp:datesOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                            <cmdp:Relationship/>
                        </cmdp:Collection>
                        <cmdp:Collection>
                            <cmdp:identificationArea>
                                <cmdp:referencecode>ICTY/ JCR/19</cmdp:referencecode>
                                <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>2002-2016</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                                <cmdp:levelOfDescription>Sub-sub-fonds</cmdp:levelOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:extentAndMedium>11 linear metres of physical records; 3,228 digital items</cmdp:extentAndMedium>
                                <cmdp:titles>
                                    <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić and Veselin Šljivančanin (IT-95-13/1)</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                                </cmdp:titles>
                            </cmdp:identificationArea>
                            <cmdp:contextArea/>
                            <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                                <cmdp:scopeAndContent>The sub-sub-fonds contains judicial case records for the Mrkšić et al. case (IT-95-13/1).  Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić, Veselin Šljivančanin were initially indicted in November 1995 and charged with Crimes against humanity, Grave breaches of the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and Violations of laws or customs of war for crimes allegedlly committed in Vukovar, Croatia in November of 1991. Following the arrest or voluntary surrender of the accused in 2002 and 2003, the indictment was amended several times to include charges of Crimea against humanity and Violations of laws or customs of war. At the trial, Mrkšić was found guilty of murder, torture and cruel treatment as Violations of laws or customs of war and sentenced to 20 years of imrpisonment; Šljivančanin was found guilty of torture as a Violation of laws or customs of war and sentenced to 5 years of imprisonment; while Miroslav Radić was acquitted of all charges. Following the appeal by Mrkšić and Šljivančanin, as well as the OTP, the ICTY Appeals Chamber confirmed the sentence for Mrkšić, found Šljivančanin guilty of murder as violation of laws or customs of war and increased his  sentence to 17 years of imprisonment. Following the review proceedingsinitiated bz Šljivančanin  in 2010, the Appeals Chamber vacated the conviction for murder and reduced the sentence to 10 years of imprisonment. The sub-sub fonds includes records of: pre-trial proceedings, 16 May 2002 - 10 October 2005;  trial proceedings, 11 October 2005 - 27 September 2007;  appeal proceedings, 29 October 2007 - 5 May 2009; review proceedings for Veselin Šljivančanin, 28 January 2010 - 8 December 2010    proceedings related to the enforcement of sentences of Mile Mrkšić and Veselin Šljivančanin, 5 July 2011 - 17 August 2015.</cmdp:scopeAndContent>
                                <cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>Permanent retention /?/</cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>
                                <cmdp:accruals>No further accruals are expected</cmdp:accruals>
                                <cmdp:systemOfArrangement>"The records consist of:  ICTY/JCR/19/1: Filings  ICTY/JCR/19/2: Exhibits  ICTY/JCR/19/3: Transcripts  ICTY/JCR/19/4: Audiovisual recordings of court proceedings"</cmdp:systemOfArrangement>
                            </cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                                <cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>Access to records is subject to the Access Policy for the Records held by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (MICT/17/Rev.1) https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf</cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English; French; Bosnian;
                                    Croatian; Serbian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:findingAids>Catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/results); United Court Records Databaase User Guide (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAids>
                            </cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                            <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                                <cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>Public records can be found in the Unified Court Records database via the ICTY and IRMCT websites. </cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>
                                <cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>"1) For details about the case, including the charges against the accused, and a summary of both the trial and appeal judgements, see the Case Information Sheet 2) For the Mrkšić et al. case correspondence files, see ICTY/CAS/8 3) In 2002 the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13) became Mrkšić et al. (IT-95-13/1). For the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case, see ICTY/JCR/18 4) Slavko Dokmanović was originally indicted in the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13). In 1997 Dokmanović was separated to the Dokmanović case (IT-95-13a). For the Dokmanović case, see ICTY/JCR/20"</cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                            <cmdp:notes/>
                            <cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                                <cmdp:institutionIdentfier>DRE author</cmdp:institutionIdentfier>
                                <cmdp:languageOfDescription>English</cmdp:languageOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:scriptOfDescription>Latin</cmdp:scriptOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:sources>UN IRMCT Archive Catalogue; UN ICTY, Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13-I), Indictment, 07 Nov 1995;  UN ICTY, Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13-PT), Third Consolidated Amended Indictment, 15 Nov 2004;  UN ICTY, "Vukovar Hospital", Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13/1), Case Info Sheet.  </cmdp:sources>
                                <cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE Guidelines</cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>
                                <cmdp:datesOfDescription>2025-02-04</cmdp:datesOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                            <cmdp:Relationship/>
                        </cmdp:Collection>
                        <cmdp:Collection>
                            <cmdp:identificationArea>
                                <cmdp:referencecode>ICTY/ JCR/20</cmdp:referencecode>
                                <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>1996</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                                <cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>2014</cmdp:dateOfAccumulationOrCreation>
                                <cmdp:levelOfDescription>Sub-sub-fonds</cmdp:levelOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:extentAndMedium>8.6 linear metres of physical records; 1,098 digital items</cmdp:extentAndMedium>
                                <cmdp:titles>
                                    <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>Prosecutor v. Slavko Dokmanović (IT-95-13a)</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfTitle>
                                </cmdp:titles>
                            </cmdp:identificationArea>
                            <cmdp:contextArea/>
                            <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                                <cmdp:scopeAndContent>"Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić, Veselin Šljivančanin were initially indicted in November 1995 and charged with Crimes against humanity, Grave breaches of the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and Violations of laws or customs of war for crimes allegedlly committed in Vukovar, Croatia in November of 1991. In April 1996, the indictment was amended to include the fourth accused, Slavko Dokmanović. In June 1997, Dokmanović was arrested and transferred to the ICTY and the proceedings against his were severed into a separate case. The trial proceedings in the case of Slavko Dokmanović commenced on 19 January 1998 and lasted until 25 June 1998. Dokmanović was found dead in his detention cell on 29 June 1998 and the proceedings against him were terminated on  15 July 1998. The sub-sub-fonds includes records of: pre-trial proceedings, 1 April 1996 - 16 January 1998 and     trial proceedings, 19 January - 15 July 1998. "</cmdp:scopeAndContent>
                                <cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>Permanent retention /?/</cmdp:appraisalDestructionAndSchedulingInformation>
                                <cmdp:accruals>Unknown</cmdp:accruals>
                                <cmdp:systemOfArrangement>"The records consist of:   ICTY/JCR/20/1: Filings  ICTY/JCR/20/2: Exhibits  ICTY/JCR/20/3: Transcripts  ICTY/JCR/20/4: Audiovisual recordings of court proceedings"</cmdp:systemOfArrangement>
                            </cmdp:contentAndStructureArea>
                            <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                                <cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>Access to records is subject to the Access Policy for the Records held by the International Residual Mechanism for Criminal Tribunals (MICT/17/Rev.1) https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/190104-acces-policy-records-irmct.pdf </cmdp:conditionsGoverningAccess>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>English</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>French</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Bosnian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Croatian</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>Serbian
                                    Czech</cmdp:languageOrScriptsOfMaterial>
                                <cmdp:findingAids>Catalogue (https://irm-apw.adlibhosting.com/results); United Court Records Databaase User Guide (https://www.irmct.org/sites/default/files/documents/2020-09-Unified-Court-Records-User-Guide.pdf)</cmdp:findingAids>
                            </cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea>
                            <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                                <cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>Public records can be found in the Unified Court Records database via the ICTY and IRMCT websites. </cmdp:existenceAndLocationOfCopies>
                                <cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>"1) For details about the case, including the charges against the accused and a summary of the trial, see the Case Information Sheet 2) For the Dokmanović case correspondence files, see ICTY/CAS/8 3) Slavko Dokmanović was originally indicted in the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13). For the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić and Veselin Šljivančanin case, see ICTY/JCR/18 4) Slavko Dokmanović was originally indicted in the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13). In 2002 the Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić, Miroslav Radić &amp; Veselin Šljivančanin case (IT-95-13) became Mrkšić et al. (IT-95-13/1). For the Mrkšić et al. case, see ICTY/JCR/19 5) For final versions of Prosecution closing arguments in the Dokmanović case, see ICTY/PTR/2/2 6) For proceedings before the Mechanism in the Dokmanović case, see IRMCT/JCR/104"</cmdp:relatedUnitOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea>
                            <cmdp:notes/>
                            <cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                                <cmdp:institutionIdentfier>DRE Author</cmdp:institutionIdentfier>
                                <cmdp:languageOfDescription>English</cmdp:languageOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:scriptOfDescription>Latin</cmdp:scriptOfDescription>
                                <cmdp:sources>UN IRMCT Archive Catalogue; UN ICTY, Prosecutor v. Mile Mrkšić et al (IT-95-13-I), Indictment, 01 Apr 1996;  UN ICTY;  UN ICTY, "Vukovar Hospital", Slavko Dokmanović (IT-95-13a), Case Info Sheet.  </cmdp:sources>
                                <cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>ISAD(G); DRE Guidelines</cmdp:rulesOrConventionsDREGuidelines>
                                <cmdp:datesOfDescription>2025-02-04</cmdp:datesOfDescription>
                            </cmdp:descriptionControlArea>
                            <cmdp:Relationship/>
                        </cmdp:Collection>
                        <cmdp:Level4>
                            <cmdp:Collection>
                                <cmdp:identificationArea>
                                    <cmdp:titles/>
                                </cmdp:identificationArea>
                                <cmdp:contextArea/>
                                <cmdp:contentAndStructureArea/>
                                <cmdp:conditionsOfAccessAndUseArea/>
                                <cmdp:alliedMaterialsArea/>
                                <cmdp:notes/>
                                <cmdp:descriptionControlArea/>
                                <cmdp:Relationship/>
                            </cmdp:Collection>
                        </cmdp:Level4>
                    </cmdp:Level3>
                </cmdp:Level2>
            </cmdp:Level1>
        </cmdp:CollectionHoldingInstitutions>
    </cmd:Components>
</cmd:CMD>
