<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><cmd:CMD xmlns:cmd="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1 https://infra.clarin.eu/CMDI/1.x/xsd/cmd-envelop.xsd http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1733830015132 http://catalog.clarin.eu/ds/ComponentRegistry/rest/registry/1.2/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1733830015132/xsd" CMDVersion="1.2">
   <cmd:Header>
      <cmd:MdCreator>test</cmd:MdCreator>
      <cmd:MdCreationDate xmlns:clariah="http://www.clariah.eu/" clariah:epoch="1742305029">2025-03-18</cmd:MdCreationDate>
      <cmd:MdSelfLink>unl://1</cmd:MdSelfLink>
      <cmd:MdProfile>clarin.eu:cr1:p_1733830015132</cmd:MdProfile>
      <cmd:MdCollectionDisplayName/>
   </cmd:Header>
   <cmd:Resources>
      <cmd:ResourceProxyList/>
      <cmd:JournalFileProxyList/>
      <cmd:ResourceRelationList/>
      <cmd:IsPartOfList/>
   </cmd:Resources>
   <cmd:Components>
      <cmdp:Events xmlns:cmdp="http://www.clarin.eu/cmd/1/profiles/clarin.eu:cr1:p_1733830015132">
         <cmdp:EventsIdentityArea>
            <cmdp:TypeOfEvent>Armed Conflict</cmdp:TypeOfEvent>
            <cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfName>Domovinski rat</cmdp:AuthorizedFormOfName>
            <cmdp:ParallelFormsOfName>Homeland War</cmdp:ParallelFormsOfName>
            <cmdp:otherFormsOfName>Croatian War of Independence </cmdp:otherFormsOfName>
            <cmdp:otherFormsOfName>Rat u Hrvatskoj</cmdp:otherFormsOfName>
            <cmdp:otherFormsOfName>War in Croatia</cmdp:otherFormsOfName>
         </cmdp:EventsIdentityArea>
         <cmdp:eventsDescriptionArea>
            <cmdp:history xml:lang="en">"In  April  and  May  1990,  multi-party  elections  were  held  in  the   Socialist   Republic   of Croatia. The  Croatian  Democratic  Union  (""HDZ"")  won  41.5%  of  the  votes  and  two-thirds  of  the seats in the Parliament.  On  30  May   1990,   the   HDZ   candidate   Franjo   Tuđman   was   elected President of the Presidency of the Socialist Republic of Croatia. As a result of the elections,  the Serbian  Democratic  Party  (""SDS"")  gained  power  in  the  municipalities  of  Benkovac,   Donji   Lapac, Gračac, Glina, Korenica, Knin, Obrovac, and Vojnić.   On 25 July 1990, a Serbian Assembly was established in Srb,  north  of  Knin,  as  the  political  representation of the Serbian people in Croatia. The  Serbian  Assembly  declared  sovereignty   and  autonomy of the Serb people in Croatia.  On 31 July 1990,  Milan  Babić  became  president  of  the  Serbian National Council (""SNC""), the executive body of the Serbian Assembly.  On   16   August 1990, the SNC called for a referendum on the autonomy of  Serbs  in  Croatia  to  be  held  between 19 August and 2 September        1990.The following  day,  17  August  1990,  the  Government  of  Croatia declared the referendum illegal. The Croatian police  moved  towards  several  Serb-majority  towns  in the Krajina region and removed weaponry from the police stations. Serbs  responded  by   putting   up barricades in Knin and surroundings. The  referendum  was  held  between   19   August   and   2  September 1990: 97.7% voted in favour of autonomy.           On  21  December  1990,  the  Serb Autonomous Region (Srpska autonomna oblast – SAO)  Krajina  was  proclaimed  by   the   municipalities   of   the regions of Northern Dalmatia and Lika, in Southwestern Croatia. Article I of the Statute of  the SAO Krajina defined the SAO Krajina  as  ""a  form  of  territorial  autonomy  within  the  Republic  of                 Croatia"" on which the Constitution of the Republic of Croatia, state laws and the Statute  of  the  SAO Krajina were applied.   On  22  December  1990,  the  Parliament  of  Croatia  adopted  a   new   constitution,   wherein  Croatia was defined as ""the national state of the Croatian nation and  a  state  of  members  of  other  nations and minorities who are citizens: Serbs [          ... ] who are  guaranteed  equality  with  citizens  of    Croatian nationality       [ ... ] The constitutional changes had the effect that Serbs, as an ethnic group, were no longer considered a constituent nation of he Croatian Republic, but became a national minority. The use of the Cyrillic scrip as an official script was also banned. The   Serb   population   in   the   Krajina   region   considered    that    by    the  adoption  of  the  new  constitution,  they  had  been   deprived   of   the   right   to   be   a   constituent   nation   in Croatia, which would include the right of self-determination.         On   4   January   1991,   the   Executive   Council    of    the    SAO    Krajina    established    the    Regional  Secretariat for Internal Affairs (""SUP"") in Knin. On   the   same   date,   Milan   Martic'    was    appointed the Secretary for Internal Affairs of the SAO Krajina.                 On   5   January   1991,    the    Executive    Council informed   the   Ministry of Interior (Ministarstvo unutarnjih poslova – MUP)   of   Croatia   that   the   establishment   of   the   SUP   revoked   the   authority   of   the   MUP of Croatia in the SAO Krajina territory.  In   March   1991,   there   were   armed   clashes   in   Pakrac   in   Western    Slavonia    and    in    Plitvice   between   Titova   Korenica   and   Saborsko   between   Croatian   MUP    special    police    forces    and    the    police of  the  SAO  Krajina.  In  both  of  these  clashes,  the   Yugoslav People’s Army (Jugoslovenska narodna armija – JNA) JNA   intervened   to   separate   the   two   sides. Around the same time, in the spring of 1991, Serbia-based paramilitary groups began establishing themselves in various parts of Eastern Slavonia, around Vukovar.  By early 1991 the attitude of both the political leadership and the general public in Croatia became increasingly hostile towards the JNA. The JNA had been constituted as the national military force of the Yugoslav federation, but it had come to be typically perceived in Croatia as aligned with Serb interests and effectively commanded from Belgrade by a Serb dominated leadership. In the course of 1991 many Croat and other non-Serb officers and men of the JNA left the JNA, in many cases to take up arms against the JNA in Croatia. In March 1991 Croatian forces “blocked”, i.e. effectively blockaded, the JNA barracks in Bjelovar and Varaždin. Increasingly acts of hostility or aggression were manifested against JNA personnel in various parts of Croatia. By July-August 1991 a general strategy was adopted to block JNA barracks on Croatian territory by cutting off water, electricity, food supply, and communications to the JNA barracks.   On   I   April   1991,   the   Executive   Council of  the  SAO  Krajina  passed  a   decision   joining   the   SAO   Krajina   to   Serbia,   wherein   it   was   stipulated that  the   constitution   and   laws   of   Serbia,   as   well   as   the   constitutional-legal   system   of   the   SFRY,  were to apply in the SAO Krajina.  It  was  also  decided  that  a   referendum   was   to   be   held   on   the question:  ""[a]re  you  in  favour  of  the  annexation  of  the  SAO  Krajina  to  the  Republic  of  Serbia   on   the  30,h of April?,, The   President   of   Serbia,   Slobodan   Milošević,   publicly   opposed   the    referendum    on joining  the  SAO  Krajina  with  Serbia,  stating  that  the  ballot  would  have  to  read  instead  ""in   favour   of  remaining   in   Yugoslavia"";   moreover,   he   asked   that   the   decision   on   the   annexation   of   the    SAO  Krajina to Serbia, be withdrawn.   On  12  May  1991,   after   the   intervention   of   Slobodan   Milošević,   the   referendum   was   held   on   the  following  question:  ""[a]re  you  in  favour  of  the  SAO  Krajina   joining   the   Republic   of   Serbia   and staying  in   Yugoslavia   with   Serbia,   Montenegro   and   others   who   wish   to   preserve   Yugoslavia?""   with 99.8% voting in favour.  On   16   May   1991,   the   Assembly   of    the    SAO    Krajina    approved    the                 outcome  of  the  referendum  and  stated  that  ""the  territory  of  the  SAO  Krajina  is  a  constitutive  part   of  the unified state territory of the Republic of Serbia"".   On   29   May   1991,   the    SAO    Krajina    government    was    established    with    Milan    Babić    as  President.   Milan Babić appointed Milan Martić as Minister of Defence.                         On   19   May   1991,    a    referendum    was  held   in   Croatia,   except   in  predominantly   Serb   areas,   concerning    independence    of    Croatia    from Yugoslavia. 94. 1 % of those voting came out in favour of independence. On 25 June 1991, Croatia and Slovenia declared independence from Yugoslavia. However, on 8 July 1991, an  international  agreement  was  reached  that  Croatia  and  Slovenia  would  suspend implementation of their independence until 8 October 1991.                    There  were  several  ongoing  clashes  between  Croatian  armed forces and formations and the forces  of  the  SAO  Krajina  from  the  spring  of  1991,  including  in Kijevo, Drniš, Hrvatska Dubica, Saborsko, and Škabrnja. The hostilities escalated on 02 May 1991, as the Croatian Ministry of Internal Affairs (“MUP”) carried out an operation in the largest Serbian village in Vukovar municipality, Borovo Selo, in response to the arrest of two Croatian policemen the previous night. Five buses with policemen from Vukovar, Vinkovci and Osijek police stations participated in the raid. Twelve Croatian policemen and three Serb civilians were killed and there was also a number of wounded on both sides.   From July 1991, after the war in Slovenia, the JNA became actively involved in conquering territory in Croatia and the armed clashes between the JNA and other Serb forces and the Croat forces began. The military operations in Croatia occurred in three major areas: the western Croatia, in the area of Krajina, the eastern Croatia, in the area of Slavonija, and in the south Croatia, in the area of the town of Dubrovnik.   In August 1991, local Serb communities in eastern Croatia, made a declaration of their autonomy and purported to create the second of the new Serb-ruled “mini-states” in Croatia, viz, the Serb Autonomous District (“SAO”; Srpska Autonomna Oblast) of Slavonia, Baranja, and Western Srem. "</cmdp:history>
            <cmdp:DateRange>
               <cmdp:startDateYear>1991</cmdp:startDateYear>
               <cmdp:endDateYear>1995</cmdp:endDateYear>
               <cmdp:endDateMonth>August</cmdp:endDateMonth>
               <cmdp:endDateDay>8</cmdp:endDateDay>
            </cmdp:DateRange>
         </cmdp:eventsDescriptionArea>
         <cmdp:eventsControlArea>
            <cmdp:authorityRecordIdentifier>DRE_EVE_001</cmdp:authorityRecordIdentifier>
            <cmdp:institutionIdentifier>DRE Author</cmdp:institutionIdentifier>
            <cmdp:rulesOrConventions>DRE guidelines ;)</cmdp:rulesOrConventions>
            <cmdp:datesOfCreationRevisionOrDeletion>2025-03-13</cmdp:datesOfCreationRevisionOrDeletion>
         </cmdp:eventsControlArea>
         <cmdp:eventsRelationArea>
            <cmdp:Relationship>
               <cmdp:to>Battle of Vukovar</cmdp:to>
               <cmdp:category>is part of</cmdp:category>
               <cmdp:description>ID</cmdp:description>
            </cmdp:Relationship>
         </cmdp:eventsRelationArea>
      </cmdp:Events>
   </cmd:Components>
</cmd:CMD>